Herbert Halpert collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 5: Student research - Kentucky
  - Subseries 3: Mythology
    - Sub-subseries 1, Spring 1952
      - Verlinda Long (Box-folder 40/17)
      - Betty Sue Manning (Box-folder 40/18)
      - Lela K. McMican (Box-folder 40/19)
      - Maunone Mitchell (Box-folder 40/20)
      - Grace V. Noel (Box-folder 40/21)
      - Glenn W. O’Bryan (Box-folder 41/1)
      - June Priest (Box-folder 41/2)
      - Mary Ann Underwood (Box-folder 41/3)
      - Ann Vickers (Box-folder 41/4)
      - Sam G. Vineyard (Box-folder 41/5)
    - Sub-subseries 2, Spring 1952
      Saturday
      - Addie Graham Allcock (Box-folder 41/6)
      - Estelle Barnes (Box-folder 41/7)
      - Carolyn Carman (Box-folder 41/8)
      - Eva L. Creasey (Box-folder 41/9)
      - Mrs. Ida Elizabeth Dalton (Box-folder 41/10)
      - Mrs. Irene Driskill (Box-folder 41/11)
      - George W. Hayden (Box-folder 41/12)
      - Mrs. Elsie B. Joyce (Box-folder 41/13)
      - Alice Lampley (Box-folder 41/14)
      - Mrs. Juanita Morse (Box-folder 41/15)
      - Mrs. Marjorie O’Neal (Box-folder 41/16)
      - Betty Lane Wallace (Box-folder 41/17)
    - Sub-subseries 3, Summer 1952
      - Frances Ball (Box-folder 41/18)
      - Lille Vance Farris (Box-folder 41/19)
      - Mavis W. McCamish (Box-folder 42/1)
      - Lula Cain Mills (Box-folder 42/2)
      - Mildred B. Paris (Box-folder 42/3)
      - Crystal F. Parks (Box-folder 42/4)
      - Mrs. Jewell Ramey Ray (Box-folder 42/5)
      - Rosemary Redd (Box-folder 42/6)
      - Mrs. Ruby Counce Reynolds (Box-folder 42/7)
      - Venona Lillian Rogers (Box-folder 42/8)
      - J. Garvin Smith (Box-folder 42/9)
      - Mrs. Orin M. Snell (Box-folder 42/10)
      - Jessie Lee Wade (Box-folder 42/11)
    - Sub-subseries 4, Summer 1953
      - Dessie W. Coltharp (Box-folder 42/12)
      - Mrs. Maree Cunningham (Box-folder 42/13)
      - Mrs. Mary Jo Deweese (Box-folder 42/14)
      - Mrs. Alva B. Dickey (Box-folder 42/15)
      - Norman Ellis (Box-folder 42/16)
      - Carol Fish (Box-folder 42/17)
      - Mrs. Lourelle W. Forrest (Box-folder 42/18)
      - Betty J. Hancock (Box-folder 42/19)
      - Pearl I. Hartigan (Box-folder 42/20)
      - Mrs. Mary K. Hooks (Box-folder 42/21)
      - Jenne Lou Jellison (Box-folder 42/22)
      - Mrs. Edith T. Mason (Box-folder 42/23)
      - Katherine Ann Nunn (Box-folder 42/24)
      - Mrs. Maxine H. Ryan (Box-folder 43/1)
      - Mrs. Wanda Lee Sarver (Box-folder 43/2)
      - Mrs. Christine Travis (Box-folder 43/3)
      - Willa Dean Waldrop (Box-folder 43/4)
      - Elizabeth Wyatt (Box-folder 43/5)
    - Sub-subseries 5, Spring 1954
      - Janette J. Barnes (Box-folder 43/6)
      - Rose Beck (Box-folder 43/7)
      - Jean Blackwell (Box-folder 43/8)
      - Sue Blalock (Box-folder 43/9)
      - Elizabeth Carr (Box-folder 43/10)
      - Ruth Chappell (Box-folder 43/11)
      - Bill Chilton (Box-folder 43/12)
      - Mrs. Doris Cloar (Box-folder 43/13)
      - Eleanor Colville (Box-folder 43/14)
        Miss Frye was the teacher for this class.
      - Esther Conditt (Box-folder 43/15)
      - Ann Davis (Box-folder 43/16)
      - Mrs. Shirley Ann Ford (Box-folder 43/17)
      - Peggy Guerin (Box-folder 43/18)
      - Sue Greer (Box-folder 43/19)
      - Peggy Jones (Box-folder 43/20)
      - Divina Key (Box-folder 43/21)
      - Betty Kreisler (Box-folder 43/22)
      - Mrs. Merrie V. McIntosh (Box-folder 43/23)
      - Mrs. Capitola McNeely (Box-folder 43/24)
      - Onie E. Mabry (Box-folder 43/25)
      - Charlotte Smith (Box-folder 43/26)
      - Nellie Strickland (Box-folder 43/27)
      - Blanton Tarr (Box-folder 43/28)
      - Coilla Timmons (Box-folder 43/29)
      - Mary Alice Trewalla (Box-folder 43/30)
      - Nancy B. Wear (Box-folder 43/31)
      - Zetta Ann Yates (Box-folder 43/32)
      - Mary Lou Bennett (Box-folder 43/33)
      - Dorothy Bohan (Box-folder 43/34)
      - Royce Cruce (Box-folder 43/35)
      - Mary Reta Daniels (Box-folder 43/36)
      - Dorothy Farris (Box-folder 43/37)
      - Glenda Fuqua (Box-folder 43/38)
    - Sub-subseries 6, Fall 1954
      - Elizabeth Glutting (Box-folder 44/1)
      - Patti Mae Hill (Box-folder 44/2)
      - Mrs. Lillian Smith Jones (Box-folder 44/3)
      - Rita McGrew (Box-folder 44/4)
      - Jean Moore (Box-folder 44/5)
      - Mrs. Jackie Pendergraph (Box-folder 44/6)
      - Donna Lynn Rudd (Box-folder 44/7)
      - Robbie Salmon (Box-folder 44/8)
      - Dorothy Paula Slettvett (Box-folder 44/9)
      - James H. Taylor (Box-folder 44/10)
      - Peggye Taylor (Box-folder 44/11)
      - Mrs. Ruth Douglas Thomas (Box-folder 44/12)
    - Sub-subseries 7, Summer 1955
      - Mrs. Mary Jane Adair (Box-folder 44/13)
      - Dorothy Booker (Box-folder 44/14)
      - Mrs. Pattie M. Fields (Box-folder 44/15)
      - Mrs. Mildred Herring (Box-folder 44/16)
      - Ruby Jenkins (Box-folder 44/17)
      - Mrs. Frieda McClay (Box-folder 44/18)
      - Irene McConnell (Box-folder 44/19)
      - Mrs. Zuaneta Phelps (Box-folder 44/20)
      - Barbara Jean Puckett (Box-folder 44/21)
      - Mrs. Dot Seay (Box-folder 44/22)
      - Mrs. Olivia Turley (Box-folder 44/23)
      - Mrs. Wilna C. Wilson (Box-folder 44/24)
      - Mrs. Anne Thompson Wood (Box-folder 44/25)
      - Tales to be corrected and typed (Box-folder 44/26)
    - Sub-subseries 8, Fall 1955
      - Mrs. Fay Ashley (Box-folder 44/27)
      - Dorothy Atchison (Box-folder 44/28)
      - Kay Campbell (Box-folder 44/29)
      - Margaret Ann Coffman (Box-folder 44/30)
      - Betty Cruce (Box-folder 44/31)
      - Betty Hughes (Box-folder 44/32)
      - Norma Ivey (Box-folder 44/33)
      - Luda Mae Johnson (Box-folder 44/34)
      - Allegra Jones (Box-folder 44/35)
      - Norma McGee (Box-folder 44/36)
      - Bonnie Moran (Box-folder 44/37)
      - Jeanette Walston Murdock (Box-folder 44/38)
      - Emily Oldham (Box-folder 44/39)
      - Phebe Katherine Pustmueller (Box-folder 44/40)
      - Donald K. Queener (Box-folder 44/41)
      - Martha Stinnett (Box-folder 45/1)
      - Mrs. Jane Taylor (Box-folder 45/2)
    - Sub-subseries 9, Summer 1956
      - Mrs. Margaret M. Baker (Box-folder 45/3)
      - Mrs. Mary E. Barnes (Box-folder 45/4)
      - Mrs. Radia Bumpus (Box-folder 45/5)
      - Mrs. Palace B. Clapp (Box-folder 45/6)
      - Wanda Durrett (Box-folder 45/7)
      - Jim Godsey (Box-folder 45/8)
      - Mrs. Junell Goranflo (Box-folder 45/9)
      - Mrs. Jessie Henderson (Box-folder 45/10)
      - Mrs. Nancy Crisp Hendon (Box-folder 45/11)
      - Joyce Holston (Box-folder 45/12)
      - Mrs. Eunia Mae Jernigan (Box-folder 45/13)
      - Mrs. Mildred S. Jones (Box-folder 45/14)
      - Patricia Sue Kincannon (Box-folder 45/15)
      - Thelma Lynn Lamkin (Box-folder 45/16)
      - Robert Marquess (Box-folder 45/17)
      - Mrs. Rebecca Neuman (Box-folder 45/18)
      - Mrs. Velna G. Paschall (Box-folder 45/19)
      - Mrs. Virginia Wright Record (Box-folder 45/20)
      - Mrs. Lucille C. Ross (Box-folder 45/21)
      - Mrs. Carole Ruby (Box-folder 45/22)
      - Mrs. Ingle Tolen (Box-folder 45/23)
  - Subseries 4: Folklore
    - Sub-subseries 1, Spring 1956
      - Carol Sue Empson (Box-folder 45/24)
      - Joyce Hoston (1/2) (Box-folder 45/25)
      - Joyce Hoston (2/2) (Box-folder 45/26)
      - Porter King (1/2) (Box-folder 46/1)
      - Porter King (2/2) (Box-folder 46/2)
      - Gerald F. McMaster (1/2) (Box-folder 46/3)
        Includes newspaper clippings on superstitions and beliefs.
      - Gerald F. McMaster (2/2) (Box-folder 46/4)
      - William (Bill) Mann (Box-folder 46/5)
      - Lacy Mitchell (Box-folder 46/6)
      - Grace Crider Paris (Box-folder 46/7)
      - Mary (Mimi) L. Reid (Box-folder 46/8)
      - Richard A. Wall (Box-folder 46/9)
      - Jane Williams (Box-folder 46/10)
    - Sub-subseries 2, Spring 1957
      - Robert Barnwell (Box-folder 47/1)
      - James R. Clinton (Box-folder 47/2)
      - Norma Cloyd (Box-folder 47/3)
      - Donald Decker (Box-folder 47/4)
      - Miss Jean Doran (Box-folder 47/5)
      - Carole Householder (Box-folder 47/6)
      - Nancy Jacobson (Box-folder 47/7)
      - Miss Dazzie Lee Jones (Box-folder 47/8)
      - Irene Kossoy (Box-folder 47/9)
      - Sybil Maxton (Box-folder 47/10)
      - Ralph M. Mero (Box-folder 47/11)
      - Patricia Parsells (Box-folder 47/12)
      - Barbara Peterson (Box-folder 47/13)
      - Anne Virginia Ryan (Box-folder 47/14)
  - Subseries 5: Special/folklore contributions
    - Mrs. Romelia Hooks Adams, 1951-1952 (Box-folder 47/15)
    - Thomas R. Jones, 1951 (Box-folder 47/16)
    - Mrs. Martha Dell Sanders, 1951 (Box-folder 47/17)
    - Mrs. Mozelle Rhodes Simpson, Summer 1951 (Box-folder 47/18)
    - Wallace D. Webb, Summer 1949 (Box-folder 47/19)
    - Mrs. Martha Galloway White, Summer 1951 (Box-folder 47/20)
    - Special folklore contributions, 1948 (Box-folder 48/1)
    - Asher, Dorothy Lee, 1948 (Box-folder 48/2)
    - Asher, Mrs. R.L., 1951 (Box-folder 48/3)
    - Folklore contributions and special contributions; English 112 class, etc, Spring 1952 (Box-folder 48/4)
    - Special folklore contributions; English 111, 112, Fall 1952 (Box-folder 48/5)
    - Folklore contributions, English 111 (1/2), Fall 1953 (Box-folder 48/6)
    - Folklore contributions, English 111 (2/2), Fall 1953 (Box-folder 48/7)
    - English 112 and special contributions, Spring-Summer 1953 (Box-folder 48/8)
    - Folklore contributions, English 111, Spring 1954 (Box-folder 48/9)
    - Folklore contributions, English 111, special contributions (1/2), Spring 1954 (Box-folder 48/10)
    - Folklore contributions, English 111, special contributions (2/2), Spring 1954 (Box-folder 49/1)
    - Folklore contributions, English 111, 112, Spring 1954 (Box-folder 49/2)
    - Folklore contributions, English 112 (1/2), Spring 1954 (Box-folder 49/3)
    - Folklore contributions, English 112 (2/2), Spring 1954 (Box-folder 49/4)
    - Folklore contributions, English 112 (Saturday class), Spring 1954 (Box-folder 49/5)
    - Folklore contributions, Summer 1954 (Box-folder 49/6)
    - Folklore contributions, English 111 and miscellaneous, Fall 1954 (Box-folder 49/7)
    - Folklore contributions, English 112 and miscellaneous, Spring 1955 (Box-folder 49/8)
    - Special folklore contributions, English 112 (1/2), Spring 1955 (Box-folder 49/9)
    - Special folklore contributions, English 112 (2/2), Spring 1955 (Box-folder 49/10)
    - Folklore contributions, English 111 (1/2), Summer 1955 (Box-folder 50/1)
    - Folklore contributions, English 111 (2/2), Summer 1955 (Box-folder 50/2)
    - Folklore contributions, English 111 (1/2), Fall 1955 (Box-folder 50/3)
    - Folklore contributions, English 111 (2/2), Fall 1955 (Box-folder 50/4)
    - Folklore contributions, English 112 (1/2), Spring 1956 (Box-folder 50/5)
    - Folklore contributions, English 112 (2/2), Spring 1956 (Box-folder 50/6)
  - Subseries 6: Work files/classified files (tales, legends, customs), 1948-1957, undated
    The files within each of these sub-subseries have been kept in their original order, as received from the donor. While the folklore of other states is included in this subseries, the majority of the material pertains to Kentucky.
    - Group 1
      - Table of contents-individual folklore collections (1/2) (Box-folder 50/7)
        Classification file copy
      - Table of contents-individual folklore collections (2/2) (Box-folder 50/8)
      - Murray State College individual tables of contents: legends and tales (1/4) (Box-folder 50/9)
        Work file copy
      - Murray State College individual tables of contents: legends and tales (2/4) (Box-folder 50/10)
      - Murray State College individual tables of contents: legends and tales (3/4) (Box-folder 51/1)
      - Murray State College individual tables of contents: legends and tales (4/4) (Box-folder 51/2)
      - Folksong Texts-typed copies for classification files (Box-folder 51/3)
      - Folksongs-Kentucky and Tennessee (Box-folder 51/4)
      - Folksong texts-Murray State College files (Box-folder 51/5)
    - Group 2
      - Folk beliefs: death signs (Box-folder 51/6)
      - Ghostly noise as death warning (Box-folder 51/7)
      - Just plain ghosts (simple apparitions in human form) (Box-folder 51/8)
      - "Things" - figures, shapes, etc. (Box-folder 51/9)
      - Vanishing hitchhiker (1) (Box-folder 51/10)
      - Ghostly passenger (Box-folder 51/11)
      - The "felt" or attacking ghost (Box-folder 51/12)
      - Ghosts explained (Box-folder 51/13)
    - Group 3
      - Folk beliefs: weather (Box-folder 52/1)
      - Don Prince; Crossville, Illinois (Box-folder 52/2)
      - Tales and legends from Eastern and Southern Tennessee and Mississippi (Box-folder 52/3)
      - Illinois, Missouri, and Arkansas tales and legends (for Midwest Folklore ) (Box-folder 52/4)
      - Mysterious lights (Box-folder 52/5)
      - Mysteries about places (Box-folder 52/6)
      - Mysterious sounds/noises (Box-folder 52/7)
      - The "felt" or attacking ghost (interfering) (Box-folder 52/8)
      - Strange occurrences (not supernatural) (Box-folder 52/9)
      - Supernatural (ghostly) action/behavior of objects (Box-folder 52/10)
      - Ghost story cycles (Box-folder 52/11)
      - The seeking ghost (Box-folder 52/12)
      - Ghost as person (Box-folder 52/13)
      - Headless ghost (Box-folder 52/14)
      - Vanishing hitchhiker (2) (Box-folder 52/15)
      - Ghostly passenger (Box-folder 52/16)
      - Ghostly animal (Box-folder 52/17)
      - Ghost image: outline, shadow, figure (Box-folder 52/18)
      - Ghost image: the face/figure in the window (Box-folder 52/19)
      - Ghost as shape [undefined, vapor, etc.] (Box-folder 52/20)
      - Ghostly noise or voice (Box-folder 53/1)
      - Several varied ghostly manifestations (Box-folder 53/2)
      - Ghost’s treasure (Box-folder 53/3)
      - Poltergeists and ghostly tricks (Box-folder 53/4)
      - Deadly ghost (Box-folder 53/5)
    - Group 4
      - Ineradicable blood stain (Box-folder 53/6)
      - "Bell witch" legend (polergeist) (1) (Box-folder 53/7)
      - Mysteries about places: Harpending House, etc. (Box-folder 53/8)
      - "Laying" ghosts (Box-folder 53/9)
      - Ghosts, haunts [miscellaneous stories] (Box-folder 53/10)
      - Not to be used [miscellaneous stories] (Box-folder 53/11)
        Includes a section on "Ghostly American Legends," removed from a copy of Life magazine (October 28, 1957).
      - Water witching (Box-folder 53/12)
      - Fairies, pixies, little people (Box-folder 53/13)
      - Supernatural: pain in amputated limb (Box-folder 53/14)
      - Seeming dead revive (Box-folder 53/15)
      - Not usable, I think [miscellaneous stories] (Box-folder 53/16)
      - Other states-ghosts and scary (pulled from state folder stories) (Box-folder 53/17)
    - Group 5
      - Ghost as person (Box-folder 53/18)
      - Fake ghosts (Box-folder 53/19)
      - Supernatural (ghostly) action/behavior of objects (Box-folder 53/20)
      - Ghosts explained and fake ghosts (Box-folder 53/21)
    - Group 6
      - Poltergeists and ghostly tricks (Box-folder 54/1)
      - Several and varied ghostly manifestations - haunted house mixtures (Box-folder 54/2)
      - Ghost’s treasure: the helpful revealing ghost (Box-folder 54/3)
      - Notes on animal ghosts (Box-folder 54/4)
      - Animal ghosts (Box-folder 54/5)
      - Helpful ghosts - advising, reproving, warning (Box-folder 54/6)
      - Ghosts, phantom dogs, etc. - excerpts from publications (Box-folder 54/7)
      - The seeking ghost or searching with purpose (Box-folder 54/8)
      - Avenging/dangerous ghosts (Box-folder 54/9)
      - Supernatural (miscellaneous stories) (Box-folder 54/10)
      - Other ghostly animals (Box-folder 54/11)
      - Ghostly lights (Box-folder 54/12)
      - Ghostly sounds (and one smell) (Box-folder 54/13)
      - Ghostly light as death warning (Box-folder 54/14)
      - Casket visions, etc. as death warning (Box-folder 54/15)
      - Ghost as person as death warning (Box-folder 54/16)
    - Group 7
      - Kentucky/Tennessee (Murray State College) collection (Box-folder 54/17)
      - Notes for projected books (Kentucky-Tennessee) (Box-folder 54/18)
      - Folklore (Fall 1953) to be typed (Box-folder 54/19)
      - Folklore customs: sickness, death, and burial (Box-folder 54/20)
      - Witchcraft (Box-folder 54/21)
      - Witches and witchcraft (Box-folder 55/1)
    - Group 8
      - Devil stories (Box-folder 55/2)
      - The devil (serious-moral) (Box-folder 55/3)
      - Retribution, curses, punishment (Box-folder 55/4)
      - Supernatural punishments for sin (sacrilege, etc.) (from God) (Box-folder 55/5)
      - Supernatural music and dance: devil, fairy, ghost, "air," cave (Box-folder 55/6)
      - Other world, contacts with (Box-folder 55/7)
      - Religious legends (Box-folder 55/8)
      - Ghost image: the face/figure in the window (Box-folder 55/9)
      - Supernatural power, from God - healers from devil (and witches) (Box-folder 55/10)
      - Hoodoo (Negro) (Box-folder 55/11)
      - Persons with mysterious power or knowledge (Box-folder 55/12)
      - Headless ghost - under "just plain" (Box-folder 55/13)
      - Mysterious sounds and screams (Box-folder 55/14)
      - Scared men: rising/moving corpse (Box-folder 55/15)
      - Scared men: racing a ghost - humorous (Box-folder 55/16)
      - Supposed ghost or corpse speaks (Box-folder 55/17)
      - Ghost returns for missing member told as scary tales - "I gotcha!" (Box-folder 55/18)
      - Humorous tales of people scared by ghost (Box-folder 55/19)
      - Camp stories (Box-folder 55/20)
    - Group 9
      - Tables of contents, individual collections (Box-folder 55/21)
      - Folk customs: social eating (Box-folder 56/1)
      - Folk customs: social disapproval (Box-folder 56/2)
      - Folk customs: farm work (Box-folder 56/3)
      - Folk customs: other work (Box-folder 56/4)
      - Folk customs: school (Box-folder 56/5)
      - To be filed in proper folders [miscellaneous stories] (Box-folder 56/6)
      - Miscellany (Box-folder 56/7)
      - Unsorted folklore material from Murray State College (Box-folder 56/8)
        Includes a photo of an unidentified African American male banjo player
      - Folk beliefs (assorted) (Box-folder 56/9)
      - School children stories (Box-folder 56/10)
      - Origin legends: plants (Box-folder 56/11)
      - Folk beliefs: curers and cures (Box-folder 56/12)
      - Farm customs-swapping work [wheat thrashing, tobacco cutting, hog killing, etc.] (Box-folder 56/13)
      - Punishment: spanking (Box-folder 56/14)
      - Folk customs: log rolling / wheat thrashing (Box-folder 56/15)
    - Group 10
      - Folk customs: social eating (Box-folder 56/16)
      - Dinner on the grounds (Box-folder 56/17)
      - Folk customs: church - work file copy (Box-folder 56/18)
      - Folk customs: church - classification file copy (Box-folder 57/1)
      - Folk beliefs: household (Box-folder 57/2)
      - Communal eating customs (Box-folder 57/3)
      - Folk customs: parties, dances (Box-folder 57/4)
      - Folk beliefs: miscellaneous (Box-folder 57/5)
      - Folk beliefs: weather (Box-folder 57/6)
      - Miscellaneous customs (Box-folder 57/7)
      - Folk customs: family (Box-folder 57/8)
      - Negro beliefs and customs (Box-folder 57/9)
      - Folk customs: sickness, death and burial (Box-folder 57/10)
      - Folk customs: food and eating (Box-folder 57/11)
      - Folk customs: family (Box-folder 57/12)
      - Folk customs: holidays (Box-folder 57/13)
      - Folk customs: parties (Box-folder 57/14)
      - Folk customs: hoaxes (Box-folder 57/15)
    - Group 11
      - Origin legends: people (Box-folder 57/16)
      - Animal tales (Box-folder 57/17)
      - Fables of apologues (Box-folder 57/18)
      - Origin legends: animals, birds (Box-folder 57/19)
      - Legendary characters: Kentucky (Box-folder 57/20)
      - Legendary characters: Tennessee (Box-folder 57/21)
      - Legendary characters: United States, general (Box-folder 57/22)
      - Legendary characters: Jesse James (Box-folder 57/23)
      - Odd or unusual characters (Box-folder 57/24)
      - Indians: historical traditions (Box-folder 57/25)
      - Civil War and guerilla stories (Box-folder 57/26)
      - Night riders: legends and traditions (1) (Box-folder 58/1)
    - Group 12
      - Night riders: legends and traditions (2) (Box-folder 58/2)
      - Crimes, criminals and punishments (Box-folder 58/3)
      - "Bell witch" legend (poltergeist) (2) (Box-folder 58/4)
      - Witches and witchcraft (Box-folder 58/5)
      - Supernatural: music and dance - devil, fairy, ghost, "air," cave (Box-folder 58/6)
      - Fairies, pixies, little people (Box-folder 58/7)
      - Other world, contacts with (Box-folder 58/8)
      - Treasure legends: lost, buried (Box-folder 58/9)
      - Retribution, curses, punishment (Box-folder 58/10)
      - Religious legends (Box-folder 58/11)
      - Supernatural: pain in amputated limb (Box-folder 58/12)
      - Ineradicable bloodstain (Box-folder 58/13)
      - Persons with mysterious power or knowledge (Box-folder 58/14)
      - Future predicted (fate) (Box-folder 58/15)
      - Future predicted: divining for husband (Box-folder 58/16)
    - Group 13
      - Anecdote: ghost explained (Box-folder 58/17)
      - Sham/fake ghosts (Box-folder 58/18)
      - Scared men-humorous (Box-folder 58/19)
      - Scared men: rising/moving corpse (Box-folder 58/20)
      - Scared men: dividing nut in graveyard, thieves in graveyard (1/2) (Box-folder 59/1)
      - Scared men: dividing nut in graveyard, thieves in graveyard (2/2) (Box-folder 59/2)
      - Scared men: hitchhiker in hearse (1) (Box-folder 59/3)
      - Scared men: the scarer scared (Box-folder 59/4)
      - Scared men: running from talking ghost/animal (Box-folder 59/5)
      - Scared Men-humorous (Box-folder 59/6)
      - Scared Men: the scarer scared (ghost prank backfires) (Box-folder 59/7)
      - Scaring a/the scared Negro (white humor) (Box-folder 59/8)
      - Scared men: hitchhiker in hearse (2) (Box-folder 59/9)
      - Horror stories: died of fear (fork in grave) (Box-folder 59/10)
      - Horror stories: buried alive (Box-folder 59/11)
      - Horror stories (Box-folder 59/12)
      - The absurd Negro: a stereotype (Box-folder 59/13)
      - College tales (Box-folder 59/14)
      - Tales for children (Box-folder 59/15)
      - Mock-origin tales (Box-folder 59/16)
      - Classical myths - modernized (Box-folder 59/17)
      - Strange occurrences (not supernatural) (Box-folder 59/18)
      - Odd or unusual characters (Box-folder 59/19)
      - Family and local legends (Box-folder 59/20)
      - Legendary characters: Tennessee (Box-folder 59/21)
      - Legendary characters: Kentucky (Box-folder 59/22)
      - Crimes, criminals, and punishments (hangings, lynchings, etc) (Box-folder 59/23)
      - Legendary characters: United States, general (Box-folder 59/24)
      - Legendary characters: Jesse James (Box-folder 59/25)
      - Indians: historical tradition (Box-folder 60/1)
      - Civil War and guerilla stories (Box-folder 60/2)
      - Treasure legends: lost/buried (Box-folder 60/3)
      - Army tales (Box-folder 60/4)
      - Preacher and church stories (Box-folder 60/5)
      - Other churches and denominations (Box-folder 60/6)
    - Group 14
      - Tall tale stories: "Charlie stories" (Box-folder 60/7)
      - Tall tales (Box-folder 60/8)
      - Tall tale cycles (Box-folder 60/9)
      - Tennessee tall tale (my first fox hunt) (Box-folder 60/10)
      - Alabama tales (Box-folder 60/11)
      - Florida tales (Box-folder 60/12)
      - Georgia tales (Box-folder 60/13)
      - Illinois tales (Box-folder 60/14)
      - Indiana tales (Box-folder 60/15)
      - Maine tales (Box-folder 60/16)